So we kind of postponed that surgery. My broken pelvis and I were now facing six weeks on the couch, and I would have gone absolutely insane if it hadn't been for my friends. Spontaneous parties broke out at my house every night for weeks. I was fed. I was entertained. It was great. But that kind of enthusiasm is sort of hard to sustain over the long term, and eventually it petered down to just one friend, who would send me jokes during the day and come and keep me company in the evenings -- someone I got to know a whole lot better during this period of convalescence. And when I was finally pronounced well enough to do weight-bearing activities, we loaded a telescope in the car and drove up into the mountains to look at the Hale–Bopp comet. Yes, we are geeks. And got caught in a landslide. (Laughter) I know -- like, really? No. Just kidding. (Laughter) No more disasters. No. Just the opposite, in fact. That was 21 years ago, and for 19 of those years, I have been married to that marvelous introvert who never in a million years would have approached me under other circumstances. We have a wonderful 14-year-old daughter, who did all my illustrations. (Cheers and applause) Yeah. So, pro tip: apparently, nothing makes you sexier than needing a walker on your first date. So this isn't a story about piercings or sharks or boilings or breakings. It's a love story. It's a love story with a funny little epilogue. Now I was weight-bearing again, I could reschedule that surgery, get the spine out. But I didn't need it anymore. Turns out, when you break a bone, your body scavenges calcium from all the bones in your body -- and from the little sea urchin spine that you happen to have lodged in the joint of your finger. So yes, my pelvis is now part sea urchin. (Laughter) So to biology brain, physicist brain, adrenaline brain, warm-blooded-mammal brain, I get to add "urchin brain," with all of the superpowers that that confers. You don't need to worry, though: that I am not fully human is one of the things that my family loves the most about me. (Laughter) Thank you very much. (Applause)
Entonces, pospusimos esa cirugía. Mi pelvis rota y yo estábamos frente a 6 semanas en el sofá, y me habría vuelto loca si no hubiera sido por mis amigos. se organizaron fiestas espontáneas en mi casa todas las noches durante semanas. Me alimentaron. Estaba entretenida. Fue grandioso. Pero ese tipo de entusiasmo es algo difícil de sostener a largo plazo, y finalmente se redujo a solo un amigo, que me enviaba chistes durante el día y venía y me hacía compañía en las noches... alguien que conocí mucho mejor durante este período de convalecencia. Y cuando finalmente me unieron lo suficientemente bien como para soportar peso, cargamos un telescopio en el automóvil y nos fuimos a las montañas para mirar el cometa Hale-Bopp. Sí, somos geeks. Y quedamos atrapados en un deslizamiento de tierra. (Risas) Lo sé, piensan: "¿en serio?" No. Solo bromeo. (Risas) No más desastres. No. Justo lo opuesto, de hecho. Eso fue hace 21 años, y durante 19 de esos años, He estado casada con ese maravilloso introvertido que nunca en un millón de años se hubiera acercado a mí bajo otras circunstancias. Tenemos una maravillosa hija de 14 años, que hizo todas mis ilustraciones (Ovación y aplausos) Sí. Entonces, consejo profesional: aparentemente, nada te hace más sexy que necesitar un andador en tu primera cita. Esta no es una historia sobre perforaciones o tiburones o cocimientos o fracturas. Es una historia de amor. Es una historia de amor con un pequeño epílogo divertido. Ahora estaba cargando peso otra vez, podría reprogramar esa cirugía, sacar la espina. Pero ya no lo necesitaba. Resulta que cuando te rompes un hueso, tu cuerpo elimina el calcio de todos los huesos de tu cuerpo y de la pequeña espina de erizo de mar que te has alojado en la articulación de tu dedo. Entonces sí, mi pelvis ahora es parte erizo de mar. (Risas) Así al cerebro biológico, cerebro físico, cerebro de adrenalina, cerebro de mamífero de sangre caliente, puedo agregar "cerebro de erizo" con todas las superpotencias que eso confiere. No hay que preocuparse: que no sea completamente humana es una de las cosas que mi familia ama más de mí (Risas) Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)